There are many monsters threatening humans.
有許多怪物 威脅著人類
Many brave adventurers stepped forward bravely.
挺身而出的是 眾多勇敢的冒險家
And I,
而我
Alvin, is one of them.
埃爾文就是其中一位
Forming a party with the healer Carla,
與僧侶卡菈組隊
let's continue the adventure today.
今天也持續冒險旅程
DON'T HURT ME, MY HEALER
(這個僧侶有夠煩)
THE TITLE "NOT ONLY WERE THEY ATTACKED BY A ROBBER DURING THE JOURNEY, BUT THEY ALSO MET A GOLEM."
(此次的標題) (旅途途中不僅遭到盜賊襲擊還遇到了魔像)
"ALVIN AND CARLA OVERCAME MANY OBSTACLES AS BEFORE." That old lady
(埃爾文和卡菈如以往那樣突破重重難關) 那位老婆婆
"BUT ALVIN WAS SERIOUSLY INJURED. MISFORTUNES NEVER COME SINGLY." gave us so many herbs and food.
(但埃爾文卻受了重傷 屋漏偏逢連夜雨) 給了我們這麼多藥草和食糧
"ALVIN ALSO HAD TO TAKE OFF HIS ARMOR AND REST." It's enough for us.
(埃爾文也不得不脫下盔甲閉目養神) 夠我們吃了
"THE TWO BEGAN TO QUARREL AGAIN. THEIR RELATIONSHIP MIGHT CHANGE." Yes.
(此時兩人又開始爭吵 關係可能因此產生變化) 是啊
"THE QUARREL BETWEEN ALVIN AND CARLA" I completed the guild task
(埃爾文和卡菈爭吵的台詞明明就是本作品最重要的喬段) 多虧她 我也完成公會的任務了
"BUT IN THIS ERA, WHETHER IT'S ROLE AUDITION OR RECORDING, ACCESS TO THE RECORDING STUDIO IS VERY LIMITED." Honestly,
(但在這個時代不論是角色試鏡還是錄製工作 能進入錄音室的人數十分有限) 老實說 惹她生氣時
"ALL WORKED TOGETHER TO OVERCOME THE DIFFICULTIES. THAT'S EPISODE SIX." I didn't know what to do when making her mad.
(大家一起努力合作度過難關的第六話) 我真不知該怎麼辦才好
Be careful with the fire!
小心火燭
Kyun.
破
You made the old lady angry.
你竟然惹老婆婆生氣
What's wrong with you? You've grown up.
到底在搞什麼啊 都老大不小了
You made her angry, okay?
是妳惹人家生氣好嗎
But she was rejuvenated by Carla's magic.
但她因卡菈的魔法返老還童了
She should be crying for joy.
應該是喜極而泣
Thank you, Lord Carla.
謝謝妳 卡菈大人
"LORD CARLA" She called Carla "my Lord".
(卡菈大人) 竟然稱卡菈為"大人"
It's great to have a good ending.
事情有個好結尾也是好事
All right. Let's go back to the guild and hand in the herbs.
好 快點回公會交藥草吧
Carla, why are you so quiet?
卡菈 妳怎麼這麼安靜
Is it a sign of the end of the world?
是世界末日的徵兆嗎
Sh.
噓
What's the matter, Sister Carla?
怎麼了 卡菈大姊
Is it terrible? Is the world going to be destroyed?
很糟嗎 確定世界要毀滅了嗎
Don't move!
都不准動
If you wand too bee alife, leaf...
咬敏的花 九柳瞎推扯…
What?
什麼
Let me say it again.
重來一次
Okay.
是可以啦
What's wrong with her?
她是怎樣
Who knows? I thought she was a robber or something.
誰知道 我以為是盜賊之類的
I'm going to say it.
要開始囉
Oh, okay!
喔 好
Don't move!
都不准動
If you want to be alive, leave the...
要命的話 就柳瞎推…
No, it's okay. Not bad.
不 沒關係 還行還行
One more time, one more time, one more time.
再來一次 再來一次 再來一次
Stop clapping.
別拍了
It's okay. I understood.
沒關係 我聽懂了
Leave the cart, right? Am I right?
留下推車對吧 沒錯吧
Don't I have to start it over?
不用再重頭來嗎
No, no.
不用不用
So you'd leave the cart, right?
那你願意留下推車吧
No.
不願意
"BOOS" How stingy.
(噓聲) 小氣
Duh! Life isn't that simple.
廢話 人生可沒這麼簡單
By the way, are you a robber?
話說回來 妳是盜賊嗎
It seems you're the only one.
看起來只有妳一人
I'm not the only one.
不只我一人
I'm the eldest among four sisters.
我是四姊妹的長女
That's not what I meant.
我不是這個意思
Listen up!
給我聽好了
Why did you suddenly shout?
幹嘛突然大叫
You can't just come out like that.
妳不能大咧咧的跑出來吧
You should hide and wait for the right time to take action.
應該要躲起來 伺機而動
Since you have sisters, you'd better rob in a group.
既然有姊妹 更該一群人來搶劫啊
But my sisters are still young.
可是我妹妹們還小
A monster is teaching a human how to attack people.
魔物正在教人類如何襲擊人
I have a good idea.
我有個不錯的想法
And the naturally troublesome cleric.
加上理所當然 給人添麻煩的聖職人員
Since there are more people, you'd better take a hostage.
若對方人數較多 最好抓一人來當人質
I'll let you take me hostage this time.
這次就特別讓妳抓我當人質吧
That's great. You're so nice.
這麼好 妳人真好
But will the warrior let go of our discussion?
不過那位戰士 會放過我們的討論嗎
Don't worry. He's good at handling things according to the situation.
放心吧 他很會看氣氛辦事
Then... Is that how it feels? Do you feel uncomfortable?
那就 這種感覺嗎 會不舒服嗎
No.
不會
Then try to threaten Mr. Alvin.
再來試著威脅埃爾文先生
Don't move!
都不准動
Oh no, somehow it just...
糟糕 不知不覺就…
If you want to save her,
希望保住她的小命
And then...
然後…
Just show your talent!
就表演你的拿手才藝
What a baffling request.
真是莫名其妙的要求
Be confident, Mr. Alvin.
埃爾文先生 有點自信
It's funny anyway.
反正不管怎麼樣都很好笑
What do you mean?
妳什麼意思
I don't want to perform.
我才不要表演呢
No. Why are you sitting down? I said I'm not going to perform.
不 妳們坐下來幹嘛 就說了我不表演
Stop it. Don't be like you're going to watch a show!
別鬧了 不要進入看戲模式
Alvin. Alvin.
埃爾文 埃爾文
-Don't push me. -Alvin. Alvin.
-別催我 -埃爾文 埃爾文
Alvin, Alvin...
埃爾文 埃爾文…
Homeless dog.
喪家之犬
Geez, close your eyes and wait.
討厭 閉上眼睛乖乖等啦
Don't open before I tell you to.
等我說好前不准張開
And it has nothing to do with a homeless dog.
還有 跟喪家之犬無關吧
He's going to perform.
要表演耶
My talent…
拿手才藝啊…
Okay, I'm ready.
好 可以了
Check this out.
看好了
Headless horseman.
無頭騎士
It's almost time to go back.
我差不多該回去了
Okay.
好
Wait a minute.
等我一下
Here you go.
這個給妳
Do you really want to give it to me?
真的要給我嗎
As an apology for showing you boring talent.
作為讓妳看了無聊才藝的道歉
Thank you. Goodbye.
謝謝 再見
Be safe.
回去路上小心
You're great indeed, Mr. Alvin.
真不愧是埃爾文先生
Making others lose the will to fight. That's your way of fighting, right?
讓對方失去鬥志 這就是你的作戰方式對吧
Yes...
是啊…
Geez.
可惡
No way. The golem is too strong.
不行 魔像太強了
Mr. Alvin.
埃爾文先生
Carla, step back.
卡菈妳退後
I'll buy you some time. Run away...
我來爭取時間 你們快點逃走…
Impossible. You can't buy us any time.
不可能啦 你爭取不了多少時間
Absolutely no way.
絕對不可能
You deny it too much.
妳否定得太誇張囉
Not even if you were reborn.
就算轉生了也不可能
How annoying you are.
妳煩不煩啊
Hey, you. I'm as a forward...
妳啊 我身為個前鋒…
We're talking. Shut up!
我們正在忙 你先別吵
All right.
好了好了
Do you think you can fight with the golem for more than ten seconds?
埃爾文先生覺得自己跟魔像對打 能撐過十幾秒呢
You can't, right? Since you're not capable of doing it.
撐不了吧 因為你沒這個能力嘛
The answer hurts a lot, yet it's right.
殺傷力強又正確的答案
However,
不過
you have one thing that others don't.
有個東西是埃爾文先生才有的
Is it virtue?
是美德嗎
How hilarious.
笑死
It's me. Yeah.
就是我啊 耶
I want to lose it.
我想丟掉
I'll assist you as a healer.
我以僧侶的身份 好好輔助你
Beating a golem is a piece of cheese.
魔像這種魔物 小事一撞啦
It should be a piece of cake.
是小事一樁吧
Assist me?
什麼輔助
Are you going to use killing magic?
該不會是用殺人魔法吧
It'll be all right this time.
這次不會有問題的
I've grown after that.
那之後我也有所成長
Really?
真的嗎
Unlike someone who has stopped growing.
跟某位停止成長的人不同
Don't point at others.
不要用手指人
All right. The golem is waiting for you.
好了 魔像正在等你
I'll assist you well.
我會好好輔助你的
Will it really be all right?
真的沒問題嗎
I'll pick up your bones.
我會幫你撿骨的
That's unlucky.
不吉利
There's no way.
沒辦法了
I wish you success in battle.
祝你戰鬥順利
Golem.
魔像
I'm a man.
我也是個男人
-I won't back down. -Come on!
-絕不會退縮 -加油
-Let's fight... -Go for it, Mr. Alvin.
-一決勝負… -上啊 埃爾文先生
"ALVIN" Go, go, Alvin.
(埃爾文) 上啊上啊埃爾文
"COME ON" Come on, come on, Alvin.
(加油) 加油加油埃爾文
"GO" Let's go, Alvin.
(上啊) Let's GO 埃爾文
Challenge a battle that you can't win and recognize your strength.
挑戰沒有勝算的戰鬥 認清自己的實力吧
Shut up!
煩死了
How's the new magic, "yellow cheers"?
新魔法"黃色聲援"的效果如何
You're just adding trouble.
那只是在湊熱鬧吧
Your power is overwhelming, right?
力量源源不絕了吧
My anger is overwhelming.
是怒氣源源不絕
There should be other assistance magic.
應該有別的輔助魔法吧
Like increasing attack.
比方說增強攻擊力
Strengthening defense. The magic that's useful to the fight.
加強防禦力 這種有助於戰鬥的魔法
I see.
原來如此
I'll buy an expensive sword and shield from the town then.
那我去小鎮買很貴的劍和盾吧
I'll be right back.
我快去快回
No, no, no. It's not like that.
不對不對不對 不是這樣吧
I did such a silly thing.
看我做了什麼傻事
You haven't given me money, oops.
你還沒給我錢吧 呸嘿嘿
That's not what I meant.
不是這個意思
Since you're a healer, you should use magic to assist me.
既然妳是僧侶 就該用魔法輔助戰士啊
About this...
關於這件事
I think you can't beat the golem even if I make you stronger.
我覺得不管怎麼強化埃爾文 都無法打贏魔像
You hit a nerve in me.
您真會戳人痛處
Didn't you say it's a piece of cake? But you can do nothing.
說什麼小事一樁 結果還不是兩手一攤
I still have a secret skill.
我還有密技
What's that?
是什麼
You'll win with this, but...
用這招應該能贏 但…
I don't know why you're hesitating.
我不懂妳在猶豫什麼
Since we get here, I'd sacrifice myself.
都到這了 我就捨命陪君子吧
Let's work together to beat the golem.
兩人同心協力打倒魔像吧
Mr. Alvin.
埃爾文先生
I got it.
我知道了
What?
什麼
I'll borrow the power of the earth spirits.
我要藉助大地精靈的力量
That sounds great.
聽起來很厲害
It needs strong praying power for the spirits.
需要對精靈有很強的祈願力量
So let's pray together, Mr. Alvin.
所以埃爾文先生也一起祈禱吧
Got it. We just have to pray, right?
知道了 祈禱就行了吧
Kneel and put your hands on the ground.
跪下 並把雙手放在大地上
Keep your head down.
頭低下來
Sorry to keep you waiting.
讓你久等了
Well...
那個…
I have something to tell you before the fight.
在戰鬥前我有話想跟魔像談
This warrior hopes you let him win.
這位戰士希望你能讓他打贏
Please.
拜託了
How dare you trick me.
妳竟敢騙我
We almost reach the town.
就快到城市了
It seems someone is missing.
好像少了一個人
Maybe he's chasing butterflies again.
他搞不好又去追蝴蝶了吧
It's that golem.
是剛才的魔像
What? He's trying to tell us something.
什麼 他好像想告訴我們什麼
What did you say?
你說什麼
Why do you understand?
為什麼妳聽得懂
So what did he say?
所以他說什麼
Just say it if you don't understand.
聽不懂就直說啊
That's why I asked "what did you say?".
就是因為聽不懂 才說"你說什麼"啊
That's like you understood it. Fool.
那是聽得懂的反應吧 笨耶
Both of you, listen to me!
你們兩個好好聽人說話
So you can talk?
所以你會說話喔
I heard that monsters
聽說魔物活過長年的歲月
would be highly intelligent and experienced after living for a long time.
便會擁有高度智慧 及豐富的經驗
Don't explain it anymore.
不用再解說了
Just follow me. It's urgent.
反正跟我來就是了 事態緊急
What's wrong with him?
這傢伙到底怎麼了
He's poisoned.
他 中毒了
I think a poisonous snake bit him.
他好像被毒蛇咬到了
Mushroom monsters should have the ability to resist poison.
蘑菇類型的魔物 應該有耐毒性的能力吧
I'm an... edible... mushroom...
我是…可食用的…蘑菇…
Oh, right...
是喔…
Are you okay? Do you have anything to say?
你還好嗎 有沒有什麼想說的話
Detoxification way...
解毒方法…
Don't talk. The poison will circulate all over the body.
別說話 毒會循環全身的
Please don't say it's the last goodbye.
拜託別說這是最後一面了
He didn't say that.
他沒說啊
Sobbing, I wish, sobbing, in the next life, sobbing, we'll meet again, sobbing.
嗚嗚 我想 嗚嗚 下輩子 嗚嗚 定能再相見 嗚嗚嗚
Don't give up curing him.
別放棄治療啊
It's the first time I've seen someone sobbing.
我第一次看到有人嗚嗚哭耶
Others usually give up at this time.
通常都會在這個時候放棄
Luckily I'm here.
還好我在場
Look at his look of despair.
妳看看 他這絕望的表情
Let me show you
讓你們見識一下
holy power in the super healing list.
超級療癒清單裡的神聖力量
Are you sure it's not a blacklist?
確定不是黑暗清單
Have you forgotten that I rejuvenated the old lady young?
你忘記我讓老婆婆返老還童了嗎
But I also remember your killing magic.
但我也記得妳的殺人魔法喔
Are you ready?
做好覺悟了嗎
Whatever.
隨便吧
He's ready for death.
是必死的覺悟
Come and lean against this rock.
來 靠著這塊岩石
Right. Take it slow.
對 慢慢來
It looks like...
這樣看來…
It's okay. Calm down.
沒事的 讓心情穩定下來
I'm sorry...
抱歉啊…
She kind of does look like a healer...
有點僧侶的模樣了…
I'll put you to sleep right away.
我馬上就讓你安眠
No way. Her choice of words is like a devil.
不行 她的用字遣詞簡直是惡魔
With my holy left hand.
用我的神聖左手
What are you doing?
妳幹什麼
What are you doing with your hand in his mouth?
妳把手塞進他嘴裡做什麼
Stop it!
快住手
No, it's detoxification magic.
不行 這是解毒魔法啊
You're torturing him.
妳這是拷問吧
It's okay. I just let him spit out the poison.
沒事 我只是讓他吐出毒素
Don't dig out his guts.
別挖出他的內臟喔
It works. You spit the poison out.
成功了 你吐出毒素了
How is it? How do you feel?
怎麼樣 感覺如何
I feel... much better...
感覺…好多了…
You're a healer indeed. I thought I was going to die.
不愧是僧侶 我以為要死了
Don't be like that.
別這樣
I'm tired of being praised
司掌治癒的女神這種稱讚
as a goddess of healing.
我已經聽膩了
Look, Mr. Alvin.
你看你看 埃爾文先生
I did something like a great healer...
我做了像了不起僧侶的…
Medical officer!
軍醫
It's raining.
下雨了
There's a cabin nearby. Let's get there.
附近有個小屋 先到那吧
Okay.
好的
Golem, sorry for troubling you.
魔像 給你添麻煩了
Thank you for carrying Alvin.
謝謝你幫忙搬埃爾文
I don't know when we'll get to the cabin
要是讓卡菈大姊揹
if Sister Carla piggybacks him.
還不知道何時抵達小屋呢
Thank you very much.
真的很謝謝你
It's no big deal.
小事一樁
Let's help each other when we're in trouble.
有困難時 大家互相幫忙嘛
I can't go into the cabin. I'll leave first.
我無法進小屋 先走了
Well, we'll thank you later.
這樣啊 近期再去跟你道謝
Goodbye.
再見
I'm going to pick some detoxifying herbs.
我去摘解毒草吧
Sister.
大姊
You two get along well.
你們感情很好嘛
Fine.
還行啦
By the way, push the cart inside.
順便幫忙把推車推過來
Okay.
好
And give me the bag.
還有 把背包給我
The bag?
背包
What happened to me?
我怎麼了
I remember the poisonous gas spitted by the mushroom...
我記得 被蘑菇吐出來的毒氣…
Where am I?
這裡是哪裡
It looks like ruins... Is it a cabin?
好像是廢墟…是小屋嗎
You're awake.
你醒啦
Carla, you're here.
卡菈 妳在啊
God has heard my prayers.
神明聽到我的祈願了
A heretic.
邪教徒
What a pity. I'm an angel. It's great, right?
可惜 是天使 很棒吧
You're indeed a heretic.
果然是邪教徒
What's with your costume this time?
妳這次的服裝又是怎麼回事
Does it suit me?
適合嗎
It suits you. You totally look like a heretic.
很適合 完全就是邪教徒
It's the official costume for prayers
這是為了讓埃爾文先生恢復原狀
to make Mr. Alvin recover.
而向神祈禱的正式服裝
Are you sure you're not treating me as a living sacrifice?
確定不是把我當活祭品吧
What strange mask is that?
那是什麼奇怪的面具
How rude.
沒禮貌
Because...
因為…
I should find a more decent sacrifice. Otherwise, it's impolite to God.
必須找更像樣的活祭品 否則是對神明不禮貌
Crocodiles or goats or something.
至少要鱷魚 或山羊之類的
Don't you think you're rude to me?
妳不覺得對我很沒禮貌嗎
Hey, phew.
嘿咻咻
What's that?
什麼啊
How are you feeling?
身體感覺如何
A lot better.
輕鬆多了
But you didn't put your hand in my mouth too, did you?
但妳該不會也把手 塞進我的嘴巴裡吧
Sorry, I'm out of magic power. I can't use that magic.
抱歉 我的魔力用完了 無法使用那個魔法
I'm sorry.
對不起sorry
I'm saved.
得救了
How did you detoxify me?
那妳是怎麼幫我解毒的
With my prayers.
就是靠我的祈禱啊
It seems it's not a strong poison.
看來 不是什麼大不了的毒
Your face still doesn't look good.
你的臉還有點差
It's my look.
是臉色
Is that so?
是這樣嗎
That's it.
就是這樣
Lean your forehead over here.
額頭伸過來
It's fine. I'm okay.
不用啦 我沒事
It's the first time I've seen someone confirm the temperature like this.
我第一次看到有人這樣確認體溫
You still have body temperature.
你還是有點體溫
I'd be bead if I didn't.
沒體溫就死了好嗎
You'd better lie down and rest.
躺下來休息比較好
Cooler your forehead.
冰敷一下額頭吧
There you go.
嘿咻
Wring it out.
給我擰乾
I'm sorry.
對不起
Don't wring it on my face.
別在我臉上擰啊
Hey, you're a good man who looks handsome even when wet.
嗨 淋濕也很帥的好男人
It's not the right time to say that.
這樣說的時機不對吧
Forget it. Don't do anything.
算了 妳什麼都別做
Wait a minute.
等一下
Oh right, Mr. Alvin. Are you hungry?
對了 埃爾文先生 你會不會餓
Right, I didn't eat yet.
對喔 我都沒吃東西
I'm a little hungry.
有點餓了
I knew it.
我就知道
"HERBAL CUISINE" So I've prepared.
(藥草料理) 所以準備好了
There are many recipes using herbs in this book.
這本書裡寫了許多使用藥草的料理
Let me have a look.
我看看
According to the recipe,
按照食譜去做
both healing and delicious dishes can be made.
就能做出既有藥草療效 又好吃的料理
Which one are you going to make?
那妳要做哪道
Make... I didn't think that much.
做… 我沒想這麼多
How less you think...
想真少…
I'm sorry.
對不起
I'm such a hasty, dull and foolish person.
我是個輕率 又遲鈍 又不機靈的人
You don't have to be so upset...
沒必要這麼沮喪…
That's my charm, too.
這也是我的可愛之處
I'm sorry.
對不起
Don't be upset so optimistically.
別這麼積極的沮喪好嗎
Forget it. Don't do anything. Just be quiet.
算了 妳什麼都別做 安安靜靜的就好
"SAD" Okay.
(難過) 好
And...
還有
Well... That...
就是…那個…
Thank you for considering me.
謝謝妳為我著想
I appreciate your kindness.
我很感謝 妳的心意
I want to say thank you.
想說 跟妳道個謝
Why... Why are you thanking me while sleeping...
哪…哪有人邊睡邊道謝的…
All right. Goodnight.
好啦好啦 晚安
Goodnight.
晚安
Sister Carla.
卡菈大姊
I've picked the detoxifying herbs.
我摘解毒草回來了
Then Alvin should be able to recover...
這樣埃爾文就能痊癒…
Well. He seems already fine.
什麼嘛 看起來已經沒事了
"NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW" Title of the next episode.
(下集預告) 下集的標題
THERE'S NO OTHER MAJOR FEMALE ROLE EXCEPT CARLA IN DON'T HURT ME, MY HEALER. IN A WAY, IT'S A SPECIAL SHOW.
(這個僧侶有夠煩裡除了卡菈之外 沒有其他主要女性角色) (就某種意義上來說是部特別的節目)
"AFTER EPISODE 5, THE WITCH AND THE ROBBER GIRL APPEARED." Can you stop making meaningless efforts?
(第五話之後魔女和盜賊女子登場了) 可以別再做無謂的努力了嗎
"BUT THE YOUNG-LOOKING WITCH ONLY APPEARED FOR A WHILE AT THE END." It can't be finished within 15 seconds.
(但魔女年輕時的模樣只在最後稍微出現一下) 15秒內根本唸不完
"AND THE ROBBER GIRL WILL NOT APPEAR AGAIN." Are you a fool?
(而盜賊女子之後也不會再出現) 是笨蛋嗎
"IT'S TIME TO LET THE NEW FEMALE ROLE APPEAR TO MEET EVERYONE'S PREDICTIONS AND EXPECTATIONS." Right.
(差不多也該回應大家的預測與期望 讓新的女性角色出場) 就是啊
"SORRY TO KEEP EVERYONE WAITING. THERE'LL BE A NEW FEMALE ROLE THIS TIME." Oh, it's from the superior.
(因此讓大家久等了 這次會出現新的女性角色) 喔 是上級傳來的
MARIA DESFREM. BUT ENJOY THE ZOMBIE STORY FIRST. WILL IT MEET EVERYONE'S EXPECTATIONS?
(瑪麗亞戴絲芙蕾姆 但前半段先享受殭屍的故事吧) (究竟是否能符合眾人期待呢敬請期待的第七話)
"PLEASE LOOK FORWARD TO EPISODE SEVEN. STAY TUNED." You don't have to read the preview anymore...
(要繼續觀看喔) 以後不再拜託你們唸預告…